(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-09T18:17:37.469673",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Reine B'Day Classroom Field Trip : Food & Games with Akai Haato
Reine B'Day Classroom - Field Trip : Food & Games with Akai Haato
[Reine B'Day Classroom: Field Trip - Food & Games with Akai Haato]
Attention please, mother feathers!
Today, I've got some amazing guests here to celebrate my birthday with me!
Everyone, come on out!
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, Reine!
Wow, it's like we're in Indonesia!
Indonesia! We are in Indonesia!
I'm ready for a vacation, ladies!
Finally, an Indonesia vacation!
Anyways, we have...
Hi guys, it's me, Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
What's going on, homeslice? Let's have fun together, yeah!
We have Takanashi Kiara!
Yes, I am also from Hololive English -Myth-. I am Takanashi Kiara, and finally I made it to Indonesia again!
My second time!
Zeta!
Finally, I'm back in Indonesia!
A cute cat! Oh, what a cute cat!
Did you bring some churro? Churro?
Is this your new cat? That's my new house cat, you like her?
Oh, she's so cute!
For this year's birthday, I will get to do lots of fun activities!
So I went on location shoots in both Indonesia and Japan!
And I'll also be playing games that are popular in Indonesia with these wonderful guests! And guess what?
I'll be performing a brand-new song at the end of the stream!
So don't miss it and stay until the very end!
So first, let's take a look at the video from my location shoot in Indonesia!
Let's go!
Attention please! I'm Pavolia Reine, reporting from BSD City, Indonesia.
I've talked a lot about spicy food in Indonesia, but today I will be introducing a wider variety of Indonesian food for everyone to get to know it even better!
Can anyone guess what we'll be eating today?
Here we are at Jalarasa The Breeze, BSD! Embark on a culinary journey through the enchanting flavors of Indonesia at Jalarasa Indonesian Cuisine.
We are proud to bring you the authentic tastes of this archipelago nation. Join us and celebrate Indonesia's culinary tapestry!
First, we have perkedel jagung. Perkedel jagung are sweet corn fritters served with sambal roa.
Mmm, you know how much I talk about this sambal!
Indonesia has a wide variety of sambal from different regions. Sambal roa is a Manado specialty, and it's mainly made from chili and smoked ballyhoo fish.
Mari kita coba! Enak, yummy!
Next, we're going to take some Tahu Lada Garam!
Mmm, salt and pepper tofu, yummy!
Ooh, it's salt and pepper fried tofu complete with Indonesian aromatics.
Let's have a taste!
Hmm, this is like buttery flavor, I like it so much.
And this is a Sundanese specialty called karedok.
It's a traditional salad that uses a rich peanut sauce.
It has green eggplant, cucumbers, lemon basil, long beans, as well as bean sprouts.
So fresh!
Segar banget!
Next up, we're going to go eat some fish!
This is also my first time eating this fish or even looking at this fish.
Did you guys know that a fish called kudu-kudu existed?
Indonesia really has such a rich cultural cuisine.
I've never been in this before.
This is one of Jala Rasa's specialties.
Even the skin's so tough.
So this is a box fish, apparently.
This box fish is served with a super popular telor asin sauce.
The texture is membal-membal, you know.
The texture is bouncy, you know.
Enak banget.
It's so good.
I would recommend you guys eat this, yeah.
Yeah, I get what they're saying.
It tastes a little bit like chicken, it's so unique.
You guys definitely need to try it, even like Indo bros, you've gotta go and try this.
It's a Javanese specialty, smoked ribs served with sambal ijo, aka green chili.
Unlike the previous sambal we had, this one's made of only green chillies and other aromatics.
So the iga itself is sweet, so combined with this spicy and a little bit savory sambal ijo condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
So the ribs itself are sweet, so combined with this spicy and a little bit savory sambal ijo condiment, it makes for a really good dish.
Dagingnya empuk juga.
The meat is tender too.
The meat is so soft, I recommend this one.
And this one's a classic! You know what it is? It's the beloved Nasi Goreng!
So we have this traditional chicken nasi goreng that's cooked with terasi, yeah guys.
Terasi is a local shrimp or krill paste.
Smells so good.
I think it's known as belacan in Malaysia and also kapi in Thailand, yeah.
Let's try this.
It's a mix of sweet and spicy and savory.
And as usual, when you're eating Nasi Goreng, don't forget the kerupuk!
This is Nasi Liwet. Nasi Liwet is a Sundanese specialty rice...
You can taste the depth of flavors. Enak banget sumpah ini gak bohong.
You can taste the depth of flavors. It's so good, I swear, no lie.
No lie, this is so good.
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate! Siapa yang suka makan kangkung di sini?
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate! Who likes eating kangkung here?
So this morning glory is cooked with oyster sauce and topped with quail eggs and shrimp.
Oh look at the shrimp!
And this is Coto Makassar, a Makassar specialty beef stew flavored with cloves and braised peanuts.
The history of Coto Makassar dates back to the 16th century during the era of the Gowa Kingdom. Coto was a special dish that symbolized wealth and luxury, as it was said to be served only to kings and nobles...
...like me!
Let's give it a taste. Yummy.
Cloves too, you know guys, cengkeh, cengkeh.
Cloves too, you know guys, cloves, cloves.
So fresh when you got a cold.
So fresh when you've got a cold.
Now that we finished eating all the savory food, was really, really good.
Now that we finished eating all the savory food, it was really, really good.
Now it's time to close it with a dessert!
Es Pisang Ijo. Es Pisang Ijo literally means iced green bananas. As you can see, look at these beautiful green bananas. These bananas are wrapped in a green flour dough...
...and is served with coconut milk and pandan. Let's give it a try!
Look at this, it also has sweet coconut rice pudding and Indonesian tapioca pearls with a beautiful pink color, condensed milk, and a special Ambon Banana Syrup.
I really, really like their coconut rice pudding, taste so good.
I really, really like their coconut rice pudding, tastes so good.
There's a little bit of savory complementing the sweetness, mm.
Wow, that was a crazy meal! I can't believe the different flavor profile of every dish, from the jagung perkedel up until the dessert.
Wow, that was a crazy meal! I can't believe the different flavor profile of every dish, from the corn fritters up until the dessert.
And the portions are really big, so if you guys come here, I recommend you to come with your friends and share!
That's why everybody come visit Indonesia!
Everybody come to Indonesia!
But in case some of you are curious, but aren't ready to come to Indonesia...
well, stay tuned for the next part coming up!
Hey! It's Reine back in the studio.
Did everyone enjoy our shoot in Indonesia?
The food was so delicious.
I really wish one day if you guys could go to Indonesia, please have a try!
Alright, next up, we're gonna play our first game!
Yay!
We have to... Shh! We have two games for today.
So let's move our bodies and have a blast together!
All right, let's get started. Our first game is...
this!
Sorry, sorry, there's a bit of distraction
going on over here.
What are you guys doing?
There's feral animals over here!
Guys, did you even notice this right here? What is this?
Everybody gather around, gather around, gather around.
What is that?
Apa sih?
What is that, Reine?
You gotta tell us what it is.
Okay, okay, okay. You've never seen anything like that in my life.
Looks delicious, though.
Totally, don't know what that is.
I still don't know what that is.
Oh, you do?
Apa sih?
What is that?
Is it like... Es Cendol?
Es Cendol?
No!
Is it like... Sembe?
Is it like... Senbei?
Kind of, yeah.
Is it like rice cake?
Tofu, tofu!
Tofu? Tofu!
Okay, okay, okay. We'll we'll explain.
Okay, okay, okay. We'll explain.
So this one will be an individual competition.
It is not a team battle, and everyone will be...
competing against each other. Got it?
Yeah! Competition? Okay, okay.
So this one will be called the Royal Kerupuk Contest!
Kerupuk / クルプック
A traditional fried cracker popular in Indonesia.
インドネシアで親しまれている伝統的な揚げせんべい
Kerupuk: A traditional fried cracker popular in Indonesia.
Yeah, crunchy-crunchy.
Oh, what exactly is it? Is it like a food?
Yeah, it is.
Yeah, you can try to look.
It's so pretty, though, for being a food.
Yeah, so if you see, the start line is over there.
Uh-huh.
And then the line on this side is the turn-around line.
So you go like ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch and then...
And then when the signal is given, you begin the starting line and you have to do 5 squats.
And then when the signal is given, you begin at the starting line and you have to do 5 squats.
I did 5 squats yesterday!
No, no, no, no. Listen, listen. Only 5?
The good thing is, is that there is no punishment game, okay?
Because this is the fun... everyone can do it.
And then after you do 5 squats, you go run towards here.
And without using your hands, you jump and you just like grab it with your mouth...
and go round and round.
After 5 squats, my legs are already tired.
You can finish it with your hands, yeah.
And then when you're done, just be like, 'Hey, I'm done!' And then you run here.
And then you just shake your butt 10 times!
I'll be watching!
I'll be watching.
Yeah, ten...
You want 20?
No, no, no, no. 10 is good, 10 is good.
20 just a work life.
20 just a word.
Tennis is perfect.
Ten is perfect.
Good to know.
So like you do 10, and then once we count and give the okay, you run back.
And then straight to the back, you know, the finish line, and then...
Uh, yeah. The fastest one this round wins, I guess.
Oh.
Okay.
Is this like...
Is this an Indonesian game?
Yeah, pretty much.
It's a kerupuk eating contest.
But I don't think you shake your butt.
Oh, you don't shake your butt.
We gotta spice it up! That's Reine's original move, okay?
It's an upgraded version.
Yay!
Sure. Sounds good to me.
Well, there's a bit of a height difference, but it should be fine.
Oh, yeah. I think there's...
I mean, we're all pretty tall except...
The except me!
We can, we can...
We can measure our height here.
You can measure our height.
She just has to jump high.
Cats can jump pretty high, you know.
I'm not a cat! You are a cat.
You are a cat.
You are a cat. You'll be fine.
How about this? Secret agents are really good at jumping.
Okay, I'll jump.
Okay, really high. Okay, well, I guess so...
You know, looking at our heights, I guess me and Calli can go first.
Okay, okay.
Yay!
So Kiara and Zetta, you will be judging our hip shaking.
So you can stand...
I feel like she's going to...
Okay, Kiara is going to definitely give you more points, though, because I feel like she definitely wants to see that.
She wants to see you like throwing a bit.
She wants to see you like throwing it back.
Well, I want to see you.
I can be pretty strict when it comes to butt shaking.
Maybe because she wants to see more.
She'll make you do twice as many.
Nah, nah, nah. Got to be fair.
20 for Moricallify?
20 for Moricalliope?
And, oh, thank you. No, thank you.
Tennis is a perfect number for...
Ten is a perfect number for...
All right, all right. I never forgot to say it.
All right, all right. I better forget to say it.
20 for Mori, so...
Oh, sure, yeah, 20 for...
Okay, who's going to get into it?
Kiara and Zetta, please give us the start signal, okay?
Okay.
Hey, should we say it in Indonesian?
Okay, tiga, dua, satu...
Mulai!
Okay, I'm ready.
Tiga,
dua,
satu,
go!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5
Go, go, go, go!
Jump! Jump! Oh, oh, oh, she caught it!
Oh, it's so fast!
It's so good.
I know, so crunchy.
Woah!
Oh my god, it's going up!
No!
Mogu, mogu, mogu, mogu!
Mogu, mogu! Mogu, mogu!
Speed-eating contest!
They can't even talk right now!
Mogu, mogu, mogu, mogu, mogu!
Mogu, mogu! Don't choke!
Yeah, don't choke! Breathe!
Breathe! Breathe!
Don't choke!
Exhale, inhale!
Mogu, mogu, mogu, mogu, mogu!
Look at them inhaling the food!
Okay, they both look pretty much done?
I know. The last chewing... and, you got it!
Shake that booty! One, two, three, four, five!
You don't land 'sen'!
How now? Don't touch the kerupuk!
Don't touch it!
Did they finish at the same time?
Oh, let's finish! It's like a tie.
Hey, quit shaking that ass!
I actually think that I gave you 15, by the way.
No, keep shaking that ass! We're back. Keep shaking that ass!
Yo, babe! That seemed like a tie.
Good job, good job, though.
Okay, it was pretty much a photo finish.
But maybe we could check who made it to the finish line first?
Just like my Oumas. Do you two have an idea who made it first?
I feel like it was pretty much the exact same. We just can't be sure.
You were pretty synced up with the mogu mogu, also. That surprised me.
I didn't know that it was that hard to eat. No, it was really dry.
Yeah, it was really dry! I didn't know that.
Reine, have you ever eaten a kerupuk so fast?
No, and then like usually we eat it with drinks and other food, there is no water.
I got crumbs all over your beautiful tile, I'm sorry. It's okay! No need to clean.
But for now, I guess we should give the points to...
Ah! Oh, we got it! The ties! Okay, let's announce the times.
Please announce the times for us. Let's do that with first.
So, Mori Calliope finished with a time of 55.1 seconds!
And Reine, it was a close one. Finished with a time of 55.5 seconds!
That's 0.4 seconds difference. That was really close.
That was a great fight. Good game, good game.
Now, we can take it a bit easy. Let's get a drink.
Is it our turn? Oh, yes! Well, we take a break.
Now you guys get to eat the super dry snack.
Yeah! And shake around! That's the part that Kiara is most excited about, of course.
Let's get into position. Okay. Sounds good.
Bird versus Cat! Yes!
Wait, which one's the bird and which one's the cat?
I'm the bird. Huh? That's not it? Oh, okay.
But it's okay. Less discussion, more ass shaking, here we go.
Okay, how do you count in Indonesian? Tiga, tiga, dua, dua, satu, satu.
Go! Go!
We got it! Yes! Get back there! No teeth! No teeth!
Remember to squat, five times. And they need to be good squats.
Tiga, dua, satu. Okay, got you.
Here we go. Tiga, dua, satu, go!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5!
Oh, dang! She really went for it.
All right, technique! Oh, my lord, you're having a hard time.
You got to try again, you got to try again! You're eating nothing.
Jump, jump, jump! You can just jump, just jump!
Jump, just jump.
Ah!
Oh, try, try again. Try again!
Try again, a little higher, a little higher!
You got it, you got it, you got it!
Eat, eat, eat, eat! Come on! Eat!
Show down, show down! Come on, you got this!
Yum yum! Ooh, yummy, pretend it's a delicious macaron!
Oh my god, are you okay?
Oh, yummy! Mmm, delicious macaron!
Come on, eat it! You'll get it? Use the saliva! Use the saliva!
Just like generate some saliva, you got...
Just just keep, you got this.
Just keep going, you got this.
Mmm, macarons! Mmm, yummy! So sugary, sweet and delicious macarons!
It's like, what's your favorite food is?
It's like, what's your favorite food?
Macarons! And like, it's so hard, so hard!
She likes sweet... I ate it as soon as I could!
She likes sweet—I ate it as soon as I could!
Go for it, go for it! Kiara, you got this! Kiara, you got this, come on!
Zero point zero one, yeah! You're doing so good!
Make some... zero point five!
Good job, good job! How many times? Ten times, ten times, okay!
Zero to zero point five! Oh, I got it, I got it!
Shake that butt! You got it, you got it!
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten! Oh, Kiara, you're shaking that ass!
Haha! Reine is falling!
Oh, I got just slow pokes over here! I heard deadlines somewhere before!
I heard deadlines too! But got you hypnotized!
My favorite clock says that. Stop, stop, good job!
Your eating may have been better, but my ass shaking may have been better. It was pretty good, it was pretty good.
We can see that Kiara's was like a full meal infection. Yeah, and that thing was going crazy. She was doing circles with it. It was crazy.
I wonder who won. Yeah. Okay, let's announce both of your times too. Okay, let's go. Center, center!
Hi hi. All right. Let's go, let's go. Let's hear the times. Let's hear the times. Where's the time? We need a time.
Mmm, where they're cooking, they're cooking time. Baby cooking, okay. They'll figure it out.
Stream, figure it out by Pavolia Reine.
Yes, definitely. Don't miss it. Yay! Damn, I jumped as high as I could, but...
You were really going crazy. You were doing it with stab. You were like a superhero!
Yeah, I know. You're flying. Like a superhero!
Thank you, thank you. I tried hard. But Zeta, the short cat, she just...
I love it. The short cat. They jump really high. Mind legs!
The results are in!
[Title: The results are in!]
Oh, we got the time! Oh, right, please! What? Really?
You want that? That's it? Okay. Are we sure this is correct?
That's crazy! Okay, wow.
So, Kiara finished with a time of 1 minute and 42 seconds! Yay, pretty good! It is good!
And it looks like Zeta finished with a time of 1 minute 40 seconds! Congratulations! That's that's crazy!
So, in total, well, in total, so after the first game...
With 55 point one was it? I think one. 55.1?
With 55.1 was it? I think one. 55.1?
Kali, Kali has the fastest time! Cutie pie! I did it!
Kiara was so extra though with her. Thank you, thank you, thank you. I get extra points. That was good!
You really you really were doing circles with it. It was nice.
Kiara, Kiara, can you shake it back? Shake it back!
Ah, you can't get that for free. You missed it. You're not going to get it.
You can't get that for free. You can't get that for free. Wow, maybe maybe you can get it for free.
Oh! Sorry, Reine, sorry. No, it's okay, it's okay. We'll we'll clip that and upload a separate part of that.
Oh! Sorry, Reine, sorry. No, it's okay, it's okay. We'll clip that and upload a separate part of that.
Anyways, yo, I'm so glad it worked out cuz I really wanted you guys to try the kerupuk. I'm sorry it was like dry and stuff. There's drinks over there probably.
Anyways, yo, I'm so glad it worked out 'cause I really wanted you guys to try the kerupuk. I'm sorry it was like dry and stuff. There's drinks over there probably.
It was fun, right? It feels like I grew up in Indonesia now. Yay! Indonesian now!
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia too! It feels like I grew up in Indonesia too!
Thanks for sharing that part of your childhood with us.
Okay, I guess it's time to move on to the next game maybe? Oh, there's more games?
Yeah, but before that, before we continue, I would like everyone to watch a little bit of the footage...
from my Japan location shoot. It's going to be more food. So, here we go!
みんなインドネシアロケでの料理を食べたくなって思ったんじゃない？
Didn't you all want to eat the food from the Indonesia shoot?
でも大丈夫！東京でも本格的なインドネシア料理が食べられますよ！
But don't worry! You can eat authentic Indonesian food right here in Tokyo too!
I met an Indonesian restaurant in Roppongi, Tokyo today.
The restaurant is called Wayang Bali,
and it's a lovely place where you can enjoy
a wide variety of delicious Indonesian cuisine.
でも、
But,
I want to share my food with someone.
ということで、
So,
特別なメンバーにこの料理を紹介しちゃいます！
let's introduce these dishes to a very special JP member!
イェイ！
Yay!
はあちゃまちま～！
Haachama-chama!
世界を旅するアイドル
Worldwide-traveling idol
赤井はあと！
Akai Haato!
Thank you so much for coming!!!
Thank you too!
さっそく店内へ行ってどんな美味しい料理があるのか見てみよう！
Let's head inside and see what delicious dishes they have today!
イェイ！行こう！
Yay, let's go!
めっちゃ楽しみ！
I'm so excited!
Into the restaurant
[Title: Into the restaurant]
おなかすいた～
I'm hungry~
私も～
Me too~
料理が楽しみ！
I'm excited!
今年の誕生日は一緒に食事をしながらお祝いしたかったの
So, I have invited you out to eat with me to celebrate my birthday this year!
Happy Birthday!
本当に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming!
今年はいつもと違うことをしたくって、インドネシアの文化をみんなに紹介したいと思ったの
So, like, for this year, I wanted to try something new and celebrate my Indonesian culture by sharing it with everyone!
以前一緒にインスタント麺を食べたよね
We ate instant noodles together before, right?
だから今回は本格的なインドネシア料理を食べてもらいたくて
So, that's why I wanted you to try some real Indonesian food this time.
これではあちゃんのインドネシアレベルが上がるね
So you can level up your Indonesian!
インドネシアレベルが上がるね
You can level up your Indonesian!
次回はインドネシアへ行くよ
Next time I go to Indonesia.
Yes!
ここにも辛い料理があるんだけど 私たちが食べたカップ麺ほど辛くないはず だから安心してね
There are also like spicy food here, but I think they won't be as spicy as the spicy noodles here, so you don't have to worry.
辛い料理が楽しみなんだよね？
But you're excited about spicy, right?
I want spicy!
PEDAS! PEDAS!
Haachama, PEDAS LOVER!
I love PEDAS! Me too, I love PEDAS!
How do you say "I love PEDAS" in Indonesian?
Aku suka pedas!
私は辛いものが好き！って意味だよ
Yeah, that means "I love spicy"!
こうやって少しずつはあちゃまをインドネシアに染めるよ インドネシア料理を食べさせつつね イェイ！
See, I'm slowly turning Haachama Indonesian by feeding her Indonesian food! Yay!
Check out the menu
インドネシア料理の単語 このページでインドネシア語が学べるよ
Oh, it's also written here: Indonesian Food Vocabulary. So if you want to learn Indonesian, there's so many words here.
辛い＝PEDAS はあちゃまペダス好きでしょ そう やあ
Spicy = PEDAS. Haachama likes PEDAS, right?
焼く＝BAKAR Rakkakakkar BAKAR is Yaku Yaku Yes
There's also BAKAR. BAKAR is grill. Yes.
炒める＝TUMIS TUMIS Yeah Indonesian already Indonesian school starts now
Itameru is TUMIS. TUMIS. Yeah. Indonesian already! Indonesian school starts now!
サテ サテ知ってる？ 焼き 串焼き イエス インドネシアの串焼きですね
Satay~ Do you know satay? - Yaki - Kushi yaki! - Yes. It's Indonesian grilled skewers!
テンペは知ってる？ テンペ テンペ テンペ あ、分からないや
Do you know what tempe is? Tempe? Tempe? I don't know.
テンペはね、えっと... インドネシアでは、あの、タンパク質の... プリンセス？ プロテイン？ Yes. わあ！
So tempe is like... In Indonesia, it's kind of like the primary source of protein. Protein? Yes. Wow.
納豆に近い成分だと思う 納豆？ 納豆のいとこみたいなものだね プロテイン納豆
And then I think they kind of use the same base materials as Natto. Natto? Yeah, so they're like cousins. A mix.
プロテイン納豆 納豆は好き？ 納豆好きだよ お、本当に？ 納豆食べられる？
Protein Natto. Yeah. Do you like Natto? I like Natto. Oh, really? I haven't... Can you eat it?
試したことはあるんだけど 好きかと聞かれると分からないや
I've tried, but I don't know if I like it.
どうやって食べるのがおすすめ？ まぜまぜ まぜまぜ オーケーオーケー mix
How to... how to like Natto? Maze-maze. Maze-maze. Okay, okay. Mix.
納豆が好きならテンペも好きなはず Oh, yeah! Tempe!
So, if you like Natto, then maybe you will like Tempe. Oh, yeah! Tempe!
このDABU-DABUも辛いよ DABU-DABU! いい名前だね DABU-DABU is the sauce name AYAM PEDASという辛いチキンもあるね
There's also this is also spicy DABU-DABU. DABU-DABU! Fried chicken with... Yeah, DABU-DABU is the sauce name. And there's also spicy chicken AYAM PEDAS.
メニューもひと通り見終わったことだし いくつかオーダーして試してみよう！
Well, anyway, we went through a lot of the menu, so I guess we should order a bunch and we can try them all.
While we wait for our food...
いつもの自己紹介をやってみて はあちゃまちま～ 世界を旅するアイドル 赤井はあと！
So, can you say your introduction just in your normal? Haachama-chama! Worldwide-traveling idol Akai Haato!
今のをインドネシア語にすると... Haachama-chama idola ＝ アイドル
Okay, okay. So, in Indonesian, that would be... Haachama-chama! idola = アイドル
yang ＝ 〜である menjelajahi ＝ 〜を旅する dunia ＝ 世界 Akai Haato
menjelajahi = を旅する, dunia = 世界, Akai Haato
Menjelajahi dunia Akai Haato idola yang menjelajahi dunia
料理の準備ができたみたい！
It looks like our food is on the way!
お腹も空いてるし
I'm starting to get hungry.
さっそく食べましょう～！
Let's eat!
Okay, our first dish has arrived.
Are you hungry? I'm hungry. Let's eat!
こちらがテンペのソースだよ Dipして食べようね
And this is the sauce they give us
so we can eat together.
このソースは甘いの？ 甘いのかな？辛いのかな？
Is it sweet? I think...
Is it sweet or spicy?
お箸とスプーンが手元にあるんだけど スタッフが手で食べてもいいって言うから手で食べるね
I have chopsticks and spoons,
but the staff said I can eat with my hands!
まずはソースなしで食べているよ
First, I'll try it without the sauce.
私も食べてみるね ソースにつけよう
I'll try dipping it in the sauce.
ソースは甘さのある味だね
The sauce is, yeah, maybe a bit sweet.
これも試していい？
Can we try this too?
別に用意してもらったソースなんだけど 多分結構辛いよ
There's a new spicy one.
This is probably much spicier.
さっそく食べてみよう あ、どうなってるの？(笑)
Yay, let's try it. Ah, how is it? (Laughs)
お箸で救出しよう
We can rescue it with chopsticks!
辛い！
It's spicy!
普通のソースより辛っ
Mmm, I like it! It's spicier than...
大丈夫？ 辛さが伝わったでしょ(笑)
Are you okay? (Laughs)
You can tell how spicy it is, guys.
どっちのソースが好きだった？ 辛い方！ はあちゃまは辛いのが好きだね～
Which one do you like better?
"This one." Hachama loves spicy!
The next one we have Tahu Isi.
Then the next one we have is Tahu Isi.
豆腐を揚げてあるんだよ すごくクリスピーだよ！
Tahu Isi is fried tofu.
Look at this, it's so crispy!
この豆腐を開いてみるね… 出来上がってるんだね
Oh, it sounds good. But if we split
this tofu, there's something inside...
中に詰めてあるんだね もやしやにんじんなどの野菜が詰めてあるから ぜひ食べてみて～
There's the filling. Bean sprouts,
carrots, a lot of things. Try it!
半分にする？ うん
"Do you want to try some?" "Yeah."
この辛いソースとすごく合うと思うよ スパイシー スパイシー スパイシー
And I think it's very good if you
use the spicy sauce too. Ooh, spicy!
はあちゃまもインドネシアスタイルで手で食べてるね
Look, Hachama is already eating
Indonesian style with her hands.
もちもち ちょっと うん
Oh, it's chewy, a little bit. Mmm.
このソース思っていたよりだいぶ辛いよ 食べれば食べるほど辛くなる 結構辛いなと思って食べているとどんどん辛さが広がってくる
This sauce is so spicy. I didn't expect
it to be so spicy. The more you eat it...
インドネシアに行けばどこでも見かけるんだけど 例えば屋台とか
So yeah, you can easily see this
in Indonesia, at street food stalls.
屋台や道端で気軽に買えるインドネシアで親しまれているストリートフードだよ 屋台に行ってみたいな～
Like street vendors selling by the road.
I really want to go to a street stall!
次は レモン
Okay, yay, next food! Ooh, lemon.
これがアヤム・シシットだよ アヤム・シシット
This is called Ayam Sisit.
Ayam Sisit, yeah.
茹でたり揚げたりした鶏肉を細かく裂いて香り豊かなスパイスで味付けした料理だね 細かくほぐしてあるから味がよく染み込んでいて
So this is boiled or fried chicken
with rich aromatic spices, shredded.
ブム・ゲネップというペーストが使われているの ブム・ゲネップ
And there's an aromatic spice
called Bumbu Genep. That's the name.
多分さっきのソースほど辛くはないはず きっと大丈夫
I don't think this is as spicy
as earlier. We'll be fine.
普段はライスと一緒に食べる料理なんだけど おそらくライスを一緒に 出されていない理由は
Usually we eat this with rice, but
I think they didn't give us any because...
まだまだこれから料理が出てくるから ひとまずいただきましょう
There's still more food coming,
so let's try this first.
辛くはないよね？ アロマティックスパイスが効いてる
Not spicy, right? With... I don't know
what's in here, but aromatic spices!
あれに似てる！ イカ 干しイカ
Oh, it's like... squid!
Dried squid...
さきイカならぬさきチキンだね
Like shredded squid,
but this is shredded chicken.
お酒と相性がすごく良さそう… ビールと一緒にね おつまみに良さそうだね うん、おつまみ！
It's good with alcohol, like beer.
Yes, like otsumami!
そしていよいよメインディッシュのアヤム・サンバル・マタだね アヤム・サンバル・マタ
Ooh, and now the main dish is
Ayam Sambal Matah.
Ayamが鶏肉のことで Sambal Matahは生調味料のことだよ サンバ！？ 踊りの？ Sambalじゃないよ、Sambalね
Ayam is chicken, and Sambal Matah
is the type of sambal, yeah.
Samba instead of Sambal, right?
Spicy, spicy. So, basically,
fresh, raw, zesty. So it's kind of like
sour and spicy, and it's
finely sliced and then you pour hot oil on it.
Ooh.
Ooh, so this looks delicious.
Let's try.
Oh, is it meat?
Yes, it's chicken meat.
Ini tulang muda, my favorite.
I've heard this taste before.
It's like the Indonesian noodles.
We were supposed to comment on the dishes,
but this is nangkotsu, my favorite.
We were supposed to comment on the dishes, but it's too delicious, so all I can do is eat. What's a girl got to do?
Nangkotsu. I want to try nangkotsu.
Where is the nangkotsu?
Nangkotsu, ah, this one. Not this one. This one. Not this one. This one. Not this one. Nangkotsu...
I'm going to try more of the sambal onion.
Sambal.
Oh.
Oh, there's also shallots, fried onion.
It tastes like mie goreng.
Ah, it's sour.
Yeah, usually it's sour.
But it's not spicy.
Salty, right? Salty and fresh.
Yeah, so there are many, many sambal types in Indonesia, and this is one of them. When you get the chance, you should try more sambal.
Yay! Sate's here! Yay! Sate!
So, kore wa desune, ano, sate campur.
And then ini ayam,
this is chicken.
Chicken.
Ini beef,
beef.
Ini lamb,
lamb.
Uh, ebi,
ebi, shrimp.
Spicy chicken!
Yeah, you want spicy, right?
Can I just eat this now?
So, this is like peanut sauce.
It's so freaking good.
I haven't eat with peanut sauce. You want you want peanut sauce?
Chicken?
Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
Let's eat the chicken first. Eat it!
We eat so many chicken today.
I know.
Yeah, chicken is very common in Indonesian food, I guess, right?
Mm.
Mm, so creamy.
And sometimes aside from peanut sauce, they also put like sweet soy sauce.
It's same chicken,
but it's really different taste.
They have different seasoning, right?
Which one do you want to try next?
This one.
Beef?
Okay.
Oh, with peanut sauce?
Mhm.
Oh. Yeah, so normally the
one that the people eat the most is chicken.
Yeah, this is like beef or lamb, maybe it's a little bit uncommon, yeah.
But delicious. Yummy, yummy.
Everything peanut sauce.
The beef is delicious.
I like it.
I want to try ebi. Do you want to try ebi?
Ebi, I like. I like ebi.
Ebi is not peanut sauce.
I think.
You eat this one?
Uh, I think. I don't know.
Itadakiimasu.
I like this one. I like this one too.
Ebi, ebi, but not normal ebi.
The seasoning is so good.
It's a different seasoning, um it's not peanut sauce like the others, but it's so good.
Okay, which one's next?
It's go lamb.
Okay, lamb, let's go.
Oh, there's like onions.
Bye-bye onion.
Let's go.
Now, so the lamb does not have not in peanut sauce, yeah.
Mhm.
What seasoning is this?
It's not peanut sauce, but like it's some kind of like sweet sweet sauce, a little bit.
Let's go, spicy.
Wait, I drink.
Pedas! Pedas! Pedas! Pedas! Pedas! Pedas! Pedas!
Ooh.
Ooh, let's see. Is it how spicy is it?
Kind of like sweet, spicy.
Yeah, I see it like it slowly like
Yeah, it slowly comes around.
It's really good. I like it.
Ah, spicy!
I don't know what kind of seasoning this is, this is so good.
So, which one is your favorite?
Out of this one?
I really like the shrimp.
My favorite one is the beef.
It's just I think it's just because I never really...
これまであまり牛肉のSateを食べたことがなかったからだと思うけどすっごくおいしかった！
I think it's because I haven't eaten beef sate much before, and this is so good!
We have Mi Goreng!
Yeah! I'm crying!
No!
So I guess that's why they didn't give us like rice.
さっきの鶏肉のSateがまだ辛い！
Because the chicken sate was really spicy!
これは辛くないから大丈夫だよ
It's okay, this is not spicy.
Mmm.
This is Mi Goreng! Mi Goreng, Mi Goreng!
前にインスタントのミーゴレンを食べたでしょ？
Yeah, so you ate the instant Mi Goreng already?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
これは本格的なやつだよ
This is the not-instant version.
これが辛くなくてよかった…
I'm so happy this is not spicy.
Happy, happy!
辛い食べ物は大好きだけど
I like the spicy, but
ちょっと休憩したかったからもっとのう！
I'm happy we get to rest. No, now!
It's nice and chewy!
Ah, it's mochi-mochi!
Mmm.
And they're thick noodles!
麺の食感がなんいうか…嗯、very、にゃるにゃる。
Yeah, the texture of the noodles is, hmm, very nyal-nyal.
にゃるにゃる？
Nyal-nyal?
アニョアニョはインドネシア語でもちもちっていう意味だよ
Nyal-nyal is Indonesian for mochi-mochi.
Ah, it's cute!
Oh, it's cute!
にゃるにゃる。
Nyal-nyal.
It's あにょあにょ～
It's nyal-nyal.
各家庭でミーゴレンの味があるんだけどここのミーゴレンすっごく好きだな
Everyone has different Mi Gorengs at home, but this style, I really like this style.
焼きそばと似てるよね
It's like yakisoba.
インドネシアの焼きそばだね、甘めの焼きそばって感じ
It is Indonesian yakisoba, but sweet, sweet than yakisoba.
最初に納豆のいとこを食べて今は焼きそばのいとこを食べてるね
So, earlier we had natto cousin, now we have yakisoba cousin.
Natto cousin!
And finally, this is Bali's traditional dish called Lawar.
Lawar!
私も食べたことがなかったんだよね
That's why I never had this before.
今日が初めてだからすごく楽しみ！Yay!
Really? Yes, so this will be my first time also. Yay!
I'm so excited!
So in this dish, we have some peanuts.
これピーナッツか！お、ピーナッツ！
Peanuts? Oh, it's peanuts!
Yeah, this one is peanuts.
納豆かと思ってた！
I thought natto!
違ったや。
It's not.
そしてインゲンね
And then we have some green beans.
So green beans、英語でなんていうの？
So green beans, how do you say it in English?
Green beans.
Green beans、bunchies? Bunchies? Yeah.
Green beans, bunchies? Bunchies, yeah.
And then, so normally this is served with butaniku.
ウェ、they usually serve it with pork, but because this edition is like halal edition, so they replaced it with toriniku.
Well, they usually serve it with pork, but because this edition is like halal edition, so they replaced it with toriniku.
toriniku.
Yeah, with chicken. Chicken.
Mhm.
Yummy, I'm so excited! I wonder how this tastes like because there's also like shallots and everything. Let's try it.
Let's try it!
と、インゲンから食べてみるね
Wait, I'll try the bunchies first.
いただきます！
Itadakimasu.
Mmm, I like the inge is very crunchy. Mmm.
Mmm, I like the inge, it's very crunchy. Mmm.
Oh, it's like a snack!
確かにスナック菓子っぽいね
Yeah, it's kind of like a snack.
Yeah!
Everyone is...
塩味も効いてる
And it's salty.
おやつにつまみたい！
I want to eat oyatsu.
Yeah, yeah.
IT'S YUMMY!
Mmm, good.
めっちゃいっぱい食べたね！
We've eaten so many things!
Yeah!
おなかは大丈夫？
Is your stomach okay?
Yeah, okay.
ちゃんと別腹は空いてる？
There's room, more room.
もっとるもっとる cuz you know you know what comes after these meals for dessert?
Cuz, you know, you know what comes after these meals? For dessert?
Yes!
Okay, it's time for dessert!
What's dessert?
Yay!
And what we have here, we have mango pudding.マンゴプリン / Puding Mangga
And what we have here, we have mango pudding.
Look at these layers. It's so good.
この下にあるのはチョコかな？
What is this? Like chocolate?
I'm not sure, or like sugar? 砂糖か何かかな？
I'm not sure, or like sugar?
食べてみようか
Let's taste it.
Yeah.
Let's taste it to be sure.食べて確かめよう
Let's taste it to be sure.
Ooh.
It's pudding!
Yeah.
すごくやわらかいね
It's so soft.
Okay, wait, I'll try, I'll try.
Okay.
Mmm, it's so creamy!
And the mango as well, so good, yeah.
確信はないけどこのクリーミーさはココナッツミルクかな？
Like I have no idea, but like this is so creamy, and maybe there's like a hint of coconut milk.
Maybe. Yeah, I'm not sure.
Ah, it's creamy.
It is, it is. Wait, what's down here? この下のブラウンものは何？
It is, it is. Wait, what's down here?
What is the brown stuff?
さっきからその部分が気になってるんだよね
I'm curious about the brown stuff.
I'll, I'll get the brown one. 私がとってあげるね
I'll, I'll get the brown one.
Like caramelized?
Oh, this one, this one.
Yeah, yeah, that one.
It's caramel! キャラメル味だ
It's caramel!
なんというか、その、burnt caramelized flan.キャラメルソースだね！
Kind of like the burnt caramelized flan.
Wait, this is so good, guys.
It's nice.
And then we have more, apparently? Oh my god! もう1つデザートがあるみたいだよ
And then we have more, apparently? Oh my god!
Ooh!
This is fried banana snack. 揚げバナナ / Pisang Goreng
This is fried banana snack.
Fried banana!
So it sounds yummy.
Yeah.
So fried banana's like, it's literally banana, and then you have butter and then you deep fry it.
Must be good. バナナにバターを付けたりして衣をつけて揚げるんだよ絶対に美味しいじゃん
Must be good.
Yeah.
It's a very famous snack in Indonesia. インドネシアでは定番のおやつだね
It's a very famous snack in Indonesia.
Oh, we don't always eat it with ice cream, but it's fancy, I guess. I'm not complaining.アイスと一緒に食べることはあまりないけどファンシーだから不満はないよ
Oh, we don't always eat it with ice cream, but it's fancy, I guess. I'm not complaining.
It smells good. すごくいい匂いがするね
It smells good.
Smells good.
Mmm, yeah.
熱っ！
Hot!
バターが染みていて美味しいね
The butter has soaked in and it's delicious.
It's the best!!!
甘さ控えめでちょうどいい
It's sweet, but not too sweet.
アップルパイっぽい感じ
It feels kind of like an apple pie.
I like it.
カメラロールが黙々と食べているだけの私たちの映像でいっぱいになってるよね
Our camera roll is just full of footage of us eating silently.
今日は来てくれて本当にありがとう!
Thank you so much for coming today, Haachama!
招待してくれてありがとう! 誘ってくれて
Thank you so much for inviting me!
どうだった?
How was it?
楽しかったよ~
It was so fun!
私もとっても楽しかったよ
I had so much fun too!
今日はたくさんのインドネシア料理を食べたけど
Now that you've tried so much Indonesian food,
次は、what do we do? もっとレベルを上げるために!
next, what do we do? To level you up more!
インドネシアへ行くよ!
Let's go to Indonesia!
and now I like Indonesian food now
And now I like Indonesian food.
インドネシア料理の次は実際にインドネシアへ行こうよ
After Indonesian food, let's actually go to Indonesia!
I'll make it, I'll cook!
I'll cook! はちゃまのインドネシア料理
I'll cook! Haachama's Indonesian dishes!
お願いがあるんだけど… 日本のローカルな食事を食べに連れて行って
And I also have a favor... Take me to eat some underrated Japanese food too!
日本のみんなが普段どんなものを食べているのか知りたい
I want to know what Japanese people usually eat!
私が教えてあげるよ 日常的な食事を味わってみたい~
I'll teach you! I want to taste everyday meals~
Yummy
今後もはちゃまレイネのアベンチャーを楽しみにしててね!
So everyone, look forward to more Haachama and Reine adventures!
ということでスタジオへ戻しましょう スタジオのレイネさーん 取れますかあ~?
Let's go back to the studio! Studio Reine, are you there? Studio Reine, can you hear us?
はーい、スタジオのレイネです。So, what did you think of our trip to the Indonesian restaurant in Japan with Haachama?
Hi, it's Reine from the studio! So, what did you think of our trip to the Indonesian restaurant in Japan with Haachama?
It looks so delicious! I want to go!
I'll take you guys there next time! Please! Food, food, food, food!
Let's play our second game!
Well, just like in game one, we will be competing to see who can reach the goal the fastest.
Okay, are you guys ready? For this game, we will be using this item!
Oh wow, look at that!
Man, I wish I was a baller. I wish I was a little bit taller. I wish I had a six-foot impala.
Man, I wish I was a baller. I wish I was a little bit taller. I wish I had a 6-4 Impala.
Or a girl who look cute, I will call her.
Or a girl who looked cute, I would call her.
Whoa, the violence! Hey, this isn't soccer, all right? You knocked that off.
Okay, okay, okay. The rules for the next game is super simple. You hold this ball between your legs like you're giving birth,
Okay, okay, okay! The rules for the next game are super simple. You hold this ball between your legs like you're giving birth...
Young bingun nengun. Yes, so like this.
And you-- Yes, so like this!
And then you guys will be racing while hopping.
Aw, I thought we were going to play football. No, you're not! Next time, next year, football. Let's go!
Let's go, let's go, football gaku, let's go! And the game is called... The Bola Challenge!
Bola means ball! Bola Challenge!
Mine's definitely small just because skirt situation.
Mine's definitely small just because of the skirt situation.
Oh sure, that's why. Yeah, oh yeah.
Yeah, yeah, small ball. Hey, hey, stop. Okay, so basically...
all you have to do is hold the ball and then you start there and hop to the turnaround point, and then make it to the finish line, right? Simple, right?
Yeah, but like... Hey, simple.
Yeah, okay. Well, there's a twist actually.
To make things more interesting, we're adding two extra rules.
First, you'll be given a topic, and you have to race while talking about it.
Oh! Yeah, so it's just like... You guys are good at yapping, right?
I guess so! Yeah, now you can do that while jumping!
I never tried yapping while balling, okay? Never too late to pick up a new skill, putting your resume.
I never tried yapping while balling, okay? Never too late to pick up a new skill, put it on your resume.
Yeah, and just like before, two people will compete at a time, so make sure you keep chatting with your partner while you race.
Opponent partner, thing thing, right? All right, the yapping has...
Are you okay? Are you okay? I tried doing a trick, I saw it.
Okay, and the second rule is after you pass that point, you can try to mess with your opponent.
So if you want to tickle your opponent... Yeah, exactly. Stop. Hey, I'm not going to do that.
We tried this during rehearsal,
well, I tried and I guess it's going to be,
you know, it's kind of tiring. So it's your choice, basically.
You can just like focus on racing, or, you know,
if you have you're a little bit more mischievous, you want to tickle...
if you're a little bit more mischievous, you want to tickle...
You want to tickle your opponent? Yeah, you want to lift them up and kiss them as well, too. Are you too ticklish?
I'm not ticklish.
I'm not.
'Cause I think she might be tickling... No, I'm not ticklish at all.
Reine, use it to your advantage. Never let your opponent know your weakness.
Tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle... No, no, no, no.
But anyway, all right, everybody, let's get into position, Calli and Kiara.
Oh boy, I'm first again. Well, that's fine.
Let's go. You're already getting started, don't make it too hard for yourself.
You make it harder for yourself.
Wait, what's our topic?
Wait, wait, wait, hold on, hold on. I'm going to go here first.
Okay, your topic is 'Things I love about my cat'!
That's pretty easy, right? You guys both have adorable cats at home, so go ahead and brag as much as you want.
Okay, that might actually help me forget that I'm tired.
Yeah, cats take that all away.
So fluffy.
What about, can we talk about that cat over there?
No!
Focus on your game!
That's a secret agent disguised as a cat.
Or cats disguised as secret agents.
Are you guys ready?
Yeah, ready as ever.
All right, on your marks, 3, 2, 1, go!
Chu Chu is so fluffy and cute, she has this adorable blush right down the back of her what are you doing
Chu Chu is so fluffy and cute, she has this adorable blush right down the back of her—what are you doing?
Her tail is so fluffy and long.
Should we increase the distance? Should we make it a little further?
You still have to finish it!
Well, tell me a little bit about your cats, Kiara.
Yeah, so currently, I'm not with my cats, so that makes me really sad. But, um, my cat caretakers are sending me videos of them and they're sleeping like on the towels even though I said, 'Don't sleep on the towels because the towels are not supposed to have cat hair all over.'
But it's okay, I forgive them. I just buy new towels, so there's cat towels and then there's human towels.
That's a good idea to separate them like that.
That is so good. Oh my. Well done, well done. I respect the legwork.
I mean, this is I actually do this during training anyway. Yeah, hold the ball between my legs and jump.
So you okay, you just have that skill every muscle training session.
You trained the balling. Okay, onto let's announce your times.
Let's go, let's go, let's go. Gambare, gambare!
Well, I wonder who won.
That was close one.
It was very, very close. It was a very, very close match. So okay, Sata, please.
So, it
It's cold. Can you say my time first?
Okay, your time first. Okay, okay, let's see.
Takanashi Kiara, your time was 46.5 seconds!
That's a crazy dance move. She sure knows how to throw it down.
Okay, now Calli, it was a close one. It was a really close one.
Your time was 10.5 seconds.
I could have been a little faster, I guess.
This is me on slow-mo, I guess. Good Kiara.
Yeah, I I need to work on my feelings and... feelings.
I had an unfair advantage. I just wish I was a baller.
Well, first you got to be a little bit taller, buy a 6'4 Impala, then then we'll talk.
Well, I hope that your match will be a little bit closer.
Gambare! Okay.
Gambare! Gambare!
Take your ball. Okay, okay, sorry. Take your ball.
So I left my ball. Don't forget your balls.
Hey, can we make our balls meet?
What? Nice to meet you. This is my ball. Nice to meet you too.
Oh, well.
Should we just met? We just met.
Do your balls know each other?
No yet! No yet!
Not yet! Not yet!
Ah, they're just racing. They'll get to know each other now.
All righty. Well, then, it looks like I'm going to be tanto for this match, ayo. So...
Here is your topic. Okay? Compliment each other in Japanese!
No English, no Indonesian!
Wow, this is a good challenge for somebody, or two people, who speak three languages,
And also Kiara also speaks three languages.
So you'll have no excuse. Compliment each other in German.
German? Okay.
Guten Morgen! Guten Morgen! Danke schön, danke schön, danke schön!
Are you ready?
Yeah.
And on your marks, get set, go!
Satu, dua, tiga!
Empat, lima, enam!
Tujuh, delapan, sembilan!
Sepuluh, sebelas, duabelas, tiga belas...
Wait, wait. Did they compliment each other? I think so. I'm pretty sure I heard some compliments.
It was a little hard to say, to hear what they were saying, but they were definitely complimenting each other.
What were you saying to each other?
Um, I was saying Zetakawei, Asinagai, and then your hair is pretty, and then let's go on a date sometime...
Those are compliments!
What did you say to her?
I said, wow, Kimi wa subarashi, subarashi!
Kao mo shitsuyoi! Asashiyoi, that's good! Legs are cool! Yeah! So citable!
Yeah, those are compliments. That was successful, then. Good job, team.
And we got the times ready, maybe, too? Good job. Let's check out the times.
Yeah, let's see, let's see.
Well, do you guys know each other now? Yes.
Let's meet. Let's meet. You guys are married. You're married, you're married. All righty, fine time.
Fine, fine. Hey, I want my ball—my ball should hang out with you guys too. Oh, wow. We on—we only just met, but this is kind of fun.
Do we have the times? Let's check them out. We probably have them now. I think I could tell who won though.
Ah, got it. It was tight. It was—it was definitely closer than ours. Just like earlier, it was close.
Okay, we got it. The times, you want to say them? Short thing. Okie-dokie.
Now, Reine, your time was 12 seconds.
Daijoubu? Daijoubu? It bowls me wild.
Zeta, your time was 14 seconds.
It's a good number, so the winner of your match was Reine! Good job, bitch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Good job! How do you feel? Hmm. Yeah, I feel great, energized. Wait, it feels good.
Ready for more exercise? Yeah. Reine is rigged, she's the birthday girl, of course she would win.
Well, everyone had—everyone, you all did an amazing job. Oh, thank you. Thank you. It was fun.
We finished both games, so we're going to total up everyone's times and announce the winner.
Yes! That's right! Someone with the shortest total time—daijoubu? It's hot here in Indonesia! Wait, wait, take a break! Take a break! While I—CPR! CPR! Everyone, CPR!
You do it! You do the CPR! I'm dying! Somebody CPR please!
Daijoubu! Daijoubu! Daijoubu! You're gonna live! Daijoubu!
Jiko! Jiko! Jiko! Jiko! That's what you wanted. Good job. I'm alive.
Otsukare! I'm alive! Otsukare! You're alive! Congrats on being alive.
Do we have the results yet? Wait, wait, wait, while we're waiting on the results, here's my sick trick.
Okay, Calli, catch. Okay, I'm ready. Are you ready to catch? Yeah.
It was a little low. One more time, one more time. 3, 2, 1, go! Takamori! Takamori ball masters!
Takamori ball masters! Ball masters! Takamori nose ball! Wow, we're balling. Yeah, good job.
That was awesome, that was a sick trick. Well, we should become like a football club. For sure.
Oh, results are in. We got 'em! We got 'em! The results are in, and let's announce the winner, okay?
And let's start with the fourth place. Driver, please!
Takanashi Kiara! Four is the best number! Yeah, yeah, yeah! Last place, but I mean, first place in...
your hearts, right?
Yes!
Points placed as first from the bottom.
Oh, so going!
I'm so so going!
Also number one ball number.
Number one bowler!
You see how well she knows that ball?
Yeah, I see it.
Wow! Wow! Wow!
Okay. And then, the third place is our very own beloved house cat.
Vestia Zeta!
Meow, meow, secret agent.
Well, did you do it with her?
Yeah!
Okay, hand please! Hand please!
You got it.
It's a little cute.
Okay, good girl. Congratulations!
That's sort of a dog thing, though.
Yeah, cat, dog still the same thing.
Not the same animal. Not the same animal.
Cat and adjacent, whatever.
Okay, and in second place, just missing out on the win.
Oh!
It's...
Pavolia Reine!
Congratulations!
I know her, girl! I know her, girl!
Wait, Calli, you didn't give her the win on her birthday?
Oh, should I... Wait, what? Should I have done that? Is that like a manners thing?
No, no, no, I prepared something for the winner, so that's okay.
And that means our champion with the fastest time, Mori Calliope!
Mr. Ball?
Please don't hurt me. Ah. Please don't hurt me. Ah.
Congratulations!
Thank you. Thank you. Oh, my gosh.
I appreciate it. I have been training.
So, Mori, who got the fastest time, has earned a very special trophy.
Thank you!
Oh, trophy! I have to...
This is a very special trophy for you.
Yes! It's a very special trophy for today.
Wow, I love it!
Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Anyways, any comments? Any, you know, interview? Winner interview?
Um, this is really fun. I had such a great time enjoying Indonesia!
But more than anything, I'm glad we all got to have lots of fun on your very special day.
Reine, thank you for inviting us and sharing with us some of the games that, you know, you used to like to play and stuff like that.
It's just a really good time.
So, thank you.
No, thank you so much, Calli. And thank you, Reine, you did that for participants!
And that's all for the games. Thank you so much for playing with me, everyone!
Yay! Thank you! Thank you!
And coming up at the end of the stream, I have a very, very special surprise.
A brand new song performance!
New song, new song, new song!
But before we get there, I want to show you... uh, the teaser video for the new song and introduce some merch.
Merch! Welcome!
So, don't go anywhere and stay with us until the very end.
We will!
Yay! All right.
Now, let's take a look at the teaser video for the new song.
Okay! Let's go!
Pavolia Reine New Original Song Endless Blue 2026.09.09 24:00 RELEASE
[Pavolia Reine New Original Song: Endless Blue - 2026.09.09 24:00 RELEASE]
Haha!
How did you like the teaser video?
Oh!
Yeah! Yeah!
What are they doing?
Oh god!
You guys are so suspicious!
So, so, well, this new song is...
You know, my very first original song, Gate Open Start!
Yes! Yes!
So with Gate Open Start is the opening of an anime...
This is kind of, you know, a little bit more mellow vibe, maybe like a second season opening of Gate Open Start.
I love that!
Yeah! Reine anime when, let's go!
I watch it!
Second season, omedetou! Omedetou! Omedetou!
Well, as I mentioned earlier, I'll be performing it later, so please look forward to it!
Yay!
And now, before I perform the new song, I'd like to have my guests here...
My beautiful, beautiful guests help me introduce this year's birthday merch!
All right, everyone, get over here!
We won't let you down!
Bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, get on your wall right now!
Take me with U Acrylic Diorama Stand Illustration: Enji
[Merch: Take me with U Acrylic Diorama Stand]
Okay, first up, Take Me With You Acrylic Diorama Stand, featuring a beautiful illustration by Enji sensei of me enjoying me, ah yeah, with a beautiful view. Whenever you go to a restaurant, please take me with you!
What are you guys doing?
Get your Oshi Cats pictures!
Yeah! Oshi Cats? Don't forget Oshi Cats now!
Travel Towel MERAKYATS
[Merch: Travel Towel]
Oi, oi! Kiara, wait! Wait, wait, wait, Kiara!
Hey, wait! Kiara, wait! Wait, wait, wait, Kiara!
You have a pardon? Yes, you have a job to do.
I will introduce the second item, the travel towel!
Don't let the name fool you, this is a super versatile towel that you can use not only for traveling, but also in your everyday life, wipe your armpits, wipe your armpits!
Don't let the name fool you. This is a super
versatile towel for travel and everyday life—
It sure will come in handy at the next fest too, for example.
wipe your armpits, wipe your armpits! It'll
come in handy at the next fest too!
Travel towel, travel towel, travel towel, travel towel, travel towel, and...
Travel towel, travel towel, travel towel,
travel towel, travel towel, and...
And the third item is...
Ta-da! Mie Ayam bowl! Yay! Yay!
Ayam, Mie Ayam, Mie Ayam, oishii, oishii! Ayam! As the name suggests, this bowl is perfect for eating Mie Ayam,
Ayam! Mie Ayam! Oishii, oishii!
As the name suggests, this bowl is perfect
but it's also great for ramen, soup, and all kinds of other dishes.
for eating Mie Ayam, but also great
for ramen, soup, and other dishes.
So, I'm sure you'll get lots of use for... You can use it for anything! Anything!
So I'm sure you'll get lots of use...
You can use it for anything! Anything!
You can even put cat food into it! Yay! You can even use it as a hat! Whatever word!
You can even put cat food into it! Yay!
You can even use it as a hat! Whatever works!
Yeah, I hope this bowl helps you enjoy lots of tasty meals. Yay! Nyum, nyum, nyum, nyum, nyum. Very nice!
Yeah, I hope this bowl helps you enjoy
lots of tasty meals. Nyum, nyum, nyum!
And last but certainly not least, the fourth item—just kidding, it's not last, it's the fourth item.
And last but not least, the fourth item—
just kidding, it's the fourth item.
The fourth item is... The lovely travel partner plushie keychain! It is the perfect size to bring on all of your trips and your adventures.
The lovely travel partner plushie keychain!
It's the perfect size for all your trips.
Take this adorable little Reine in her costume with you wherever you go and have lots of fun together! Yay! Yay! Yay!
Take this adorable little Reine with you
wherever you go! Yay! Yay! Yay!
Yay, and this time, I also have a special situational voice... Spooky travel partner.
And this time, I also have a special
situational voice: "Spooky travel partner"!
It includes scary stories recorded in three languages. It's great. Multilingual is so scary! English, Indonesian, no mixed voice this time, sorry, no mixed language voice. And of course...
It includes scary stories recorded in three
languages. English, Indonesian—no mixed
voice this time, sorry! And of course...
The full set comes with an exclusive postcard bonus! Don't miss out.
The full set comes with an exclusive
postcard bonus! Don't miss out.
We also have a limited number of postcards with my handwritten signature, so make sure you don't miss out on this chance!
We also have a limited number of postcards
with my signature, so don't miss out!
I want Reine's autograph! Yeah! I want Reine's autograph! I want Reine's autograph!
I want Reine's autograph! Yeah!
I want Reine's autograph!
Hey, no, me! Me first! I'm gonna buy real fast. Smell.
Hey, no, me! Me first! I'm gonna buy
real fast. Smell.
Can you be more Kawaiify speed? Definitely not. But I'll see you guys in the pit, let's go, fighting for Reine's signature, all you guys better be ready.
Can you be more Kawaiified, speed?
Definitely not. But I'll see you in the pit!
Didn't we already fight enough? Well, I want to fight the fans now. Yeah, is it our turn now? All right, next.
Didn't we already fight enough?
Well, I want to fight the fans now. Next!
And that wraps up our merch introduction. Okay, move back, back, back, back!
And that wraps up our merch introduction.
Okay, move back, back, back, back!
Back where? I forget where I was! I don't know where I was. Here, maybe here, I think.
Back where? I forget where I was!
I don't know where I was. Here, maybe here?
This year's birthday celebration was so much fun! I got to go to different location shoots, spend time with everyone, and make so many great memories.
This year's birthday celebration was so much
fun! I got to go to different shoots and make
so many great memories.
So, thank you, thank you so much again for making my birthday so fun! I got to go to... You're welcome! Bringing it in!
So thank you, thank you so much again
for making my birthday so fun!
You're welcome! Bringing it in!
Reine is one year older.
Congrats on getting closer to me!
Your hair is turning... Yours is too!
And now, before we know it, we've reached the final part of the stream. And it is time for the new song performance!
And now, before we know it, we've reached
the final part of the stream. And it is
time for the new song performance!
Wait, hold on, I got to show you something. I'm going to get something.
Wait, hold on, I gotta show you something.
I'm gonna get something.
What are you going to get? I'm going to get... Where did she go?
What are you going to get?
I'm gonna get... Where did she go?
Is that what I think it is? My beautiful, beautiful baby!
Is that what I think it is?
My beautiful, beautiful baby!
It's the Reine bass with the stickers! You guys recognize these stickers?
It's the Reine bass with the stickers!
You guys recognize these stickers?
All right, I worked really, really hard on this so... I worked really hard on this so you all can enjoy it. So help... All right, can everyone say...
All right, I worked really, really hard on
this so you all can enjoy it! All right,
can everyone say...
The title of the new song together with me? Okay, let's go.
The title of the new song together
with me? Okay, let's go!
Endless Blue!
飾り付けた
Decorated
言葉でなんて本当の孤独を隠してたんだ
words could never hide my true loneliness.
折りたたんだ羽は見えない空に焦がれてた
Folded wings yearned for an unseen sky.
外れなら壊してしまった 散らばる破片バラバラ
If they'd break, I'd shatter them into scattered fragments.
誰かに似た色じゃ意味がないわかってるから
I know that a color like someone else's has no meaning.
旅立ちはあの青空のせいだから
Because that journey is the fault of that blue sky...
誤魔化せない憧れに気付いたから
...I realized an uncontrollable longing.
衝動に駆られて動き出した物語の先には
Beyond the story that started driven by impulse...
不安も想いさえも染めていく 想像より今迷い空が
...dyeing even anxiety and feelings, the sky of hesitation now...
広がってるはずでしょう 扉を開けいこう
...must be spreading wide. Let's open the door and go.
ヤミヤミ進む日々の 涙涙叫び痛む今日も
In days moving forward in darkness, crying and shouting in pain today too,
今更なんて言って 願いのいろは進んでた
saying "even now," the color of my wish kept advancing.
痛みなら飲み干してしまおう また乗り越えて見せるよ 私でいることにためらう弱さはもういらない
I'll swallow the pain, overcome it again to show you. I no longer need the weakness of hesitating to be myself.
広げた羽は飾りじゃないよ 鮮やかな夢を纏おう
Spread wings aren't just for decoration; let's wear vivid dreams.
その覚悟がここにあるから
Because that determination is right here.
幻想の夜重ねて ふらり漂うように歩いていたよ
Piling up phantom nights, I walked as if drifting aimlessly.
途方もなく遠くて 挫けそうになってもこの声は
Even if it's endlessly far and I feel like giving up, this voice...
羽ばたけるその時を待っていたんだ
...was waiting for the moment to spread its wings.
もう一度叫んでみるよ
I'll try shouting out once more.
終わりなんてない旅を続けたくて 進んでいく ストーリーの向こうへと
Wanting to continue a journey with no end, advancing beyond the story...
この声で果てない空を渡っていく
...crossing the endless sky with this voice.
まだ知らないはるかな青に胸を膨らませて
With my chest swelling with a distant blue I don't know yet,
無限の明日がきっと待ってるから 扉を開けいこう
infinite tomorrow is surely waiting. Let's open the door and go.
Reine B'Day Classroom - Field Trip : Food & Games with Akai Haato
[Reine B'Day Classroom: Field Trip - Food & Games with Akai Haato]